ohsweetbasil.com 2019-10-19

# Privacy Policy - Oh Sweet Basil

### _don’t miss a recipe!_ subscribe via email:

We have this Privacy Policy to let you know how we at _Oh Sweet Basil_ collect and use your personal information, and to assure you that we treat that information with great care.  We may update this Privacy Policy as our site is revised or adds new features, so please check back regularly for changes.

Our website includes links to many other websites.  We don’t control the activities or policies of other websites, so be sure you check their policies whenever you submit personal information through another website.

####   **Information That We Collect and How We Use It**

Analytic Data

We may collect analytic information about your visit to our website so that we can keep track of how our readers access our site, which content is most popular, and so forth.  This analytic information can include your browser, your IP address, and similar technical data.  This information is not directly linked to any personal information.

We may place a cookie (a tiny data file) on your computer as you browse our site.  This allows us to keep track of your activity within our site, but it does not record any personal information.  Our site will still function if you disable cookies on your browser.

We use analytic data internally.  We may also share it with web analytics companies that we partner with to develop or improve our site.  When we share analytic data with others, it doesn’t include any of your personal information, and in any case, the companies we share with will be under contract to keep it all confidential unless it is in the form of aggregated statistics.

Personal Data

We collect your email address when you sign up to receive our newsletter or updates of new content on our website.  We use this information to send out the newsletter or to send you copies of website updates, according to your requests.

We collect your name, email address, website, and other information that you choose to submit when you send us a comment about our website through our Contact form or when you submit a Comment within a content page on our site.  We use this information to communicate with you about your comments or concerns, and we post your name and comment on our site (subject to our right to reject any comment that we deem inappropriate).

We retain the information that you submit so that we can respond to your requests and keep a records of our business activities.  We do not share it with anyone except service providers such as our mailing list manager.  They are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are not permitted to use it or re-distribute it.

You can request at any time to have your personal information removed from active mailing list.  We will then stop sending you newsletters or updates. We reserve the right to maintain a copy of your information in our archives for historical and legal purposes.

####  **Security and Related Issues**

We maintain the security of your personal information using industry standard technologies.  We also use service providers who have a reputation for securely handling your personal information.

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

#### Children

Our website is not directed at children under the age of 13. Consistent with the federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13.

#### International Users

Our website is hosted in the United States. If you are accessing our site from outside the United States, you understand that we are governed only by U.S. laws.  Your personal information will be maintained and used according to this policy.  While we respect your desire to control your personal information, we are not subject to the data protection laws of other countries.

 **How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

 **Advertising**

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is [http://www.gourmetads.com](http://www.gourmetads.com/). These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

 **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

#### Questions?

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us using the [Contact page](https://ohsweetbasil.com/contact "Contact") on our website.

For information about opting out of Gourmet Ads and ad serving partners please visit <http://www.gourmetads.com/about/privacy-policy>

Effective Date: 1 December 2013
